<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>GAN on Physics to Data Science</title>
    <link>//physhik.com/tags/gan/</link>
    <description>Recent content in GAN on Physics to Data Science</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2018 23:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="//physhik.com/tags/gan/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Rough Review of WaveGAN</title>
      <link>//physhik.com/2018/02/rough-review-of-wavegan/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2018 23:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//physhik.com/2018/02/rough-review-of-wavegan/</guid>
      <description>Around a week ago, on ArXiv, an interesting research paper appeared, which is about the music style transfer using GAN, which is also my main topic for recent few months. Around a week ago, on arXiv, an interesting research paper appeared, which can be applied to the music style transfer using GAN, which is also my main topic for recent few months. There are already many researches on the style transfer of the images, and one of my main projects now is making the style transfer in music.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to GAN </title>
      <link>//physhik.com/2017/12/introduction-to-gan/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Dec 2017 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//physhik.com/2017/12/introduction-to-gan/</guid>
      <description>I want to introduce some GAN model I have studied after I started working for the digital signal process. I will skip technical detail of the introduction. My goal is to provide a minimal background information.
Revolution in deep learning As we have seen at the post of VAE, generative model can be useful in machine learning. Not only one can classify the data but also can generate new data we do not have.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Test Progressive Growing of GAN from the Github Source</title>
      <link>//physhik.com/2017/12/how-to-test-progressive-growing-of-gan-from-the-github-source/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Dec 2017 23:50:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//physhik.com/2017/12/how-to-test-progressive-growing-of-gan-from-the-github-source/</guid>
      <description>NVIDIA research team published a paper, Progressive Growing of GANs for Improved Quality, Stability, and Variation, and the source code on Github a month ago.
I went through some trials and errors to run the codes properly, so I want to make it easier to you. Why I think this post will be helpful is the Github page is not supporting to post issues to ask and answer for inquiries.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
