<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>_drafts on Physics to Data Science</title>
    <link>https://physhik.github.io/_draft/</link>
    <description>Recent content in _drafts on Physics to Data Science</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 01:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://physhik.github.io/_draft/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Fielding Independent Pitching Revisited</title>
      <link>https://physhik.github.io/_draft/2019-10-31-sabermetrics/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 01:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://physhik.github.io/_draft/2019-10-31-sabermetrics/</guid>
      <description>많은 사람들은 세이버메트릭션들을 숫자에 미쳐 경기를 즐기는 것을 오히려 망치는 사람들이라고 생각하는 것 같다. 실제로 야구의 인기는 줄어들고 있지 않은가
하지만 그건 구단의 최대한의 이득을 고려하는 운영방식에서의 변화 때문이지. 세이버메트릭스의 책임으로 돌리긴 어렵다
사실 세이버메트릭스는 내가 야구를 보는 관점을 넓혀줬고 오히려 더 재밌게 즐길 수 있게, 그리고 더 많은 시간을 써서 야구에 대해서 생각하게 해주었다.
또한 세이버메트릭스를 통계적인 것에만 국한하는 경우를 종종보는데, 실제로는 훨씬 넓은 의미를 가진다. 세이버메트릭스의 S가 바로 사이언스를 의미하는 것으로 야구에</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Parasite by Bong</title>
      <link>https://physhik.github.io/_draft/parasite/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 01:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://physhik.github.io/_draft/parasite/</guid>
      <description>밴쿠버에서 살면서 한국 영화를 극장에서 보긴 힘들다. 집에서부터 운전을 한시간은 해야 하고, 자전거로는 두시간 이상이 걸릴 거리에 한인타운 극장이 거의 유일한 곳이다. 기생충은 깐느 영화제에서 큰 상을 받았고 그 덕에 괜찮은 배급사와 북미 계약을 맺었다. 적지 않은 밴쿠버의 극장에서 상영 중이고, 이 영화 취향도 아닐 아내를 졸라 즐겨 찾는 멀티 플렉스 극장을 찾았다.
Kim Ki-taek lives with his wife Chung-sook, son Ki-woo, and daughter Ki-jeong in a shabby semi-basement apartment. The family struggle to survive, working any low-paying gigs available.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Blog Theme</title>
      <link>https://physhik.github.io/_draft/2019-10-29-hugotheme/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2019 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://physhik.github.io/_draft/2019-10-29-hugotheme/</guid>
      <description>I decided to use my own domain instead of renting the /github.io/, and also to insert Google adsense in my blog if possible. Even if I updated my blog only 10 times since Oct, 2017, the number of visitors and their sessions were steady by Google analysis. I appreicate the interest on my posts. Recently I started updating my blog again, and want to see the more industrial analytic result. At least I am sure the profit from the adsense will cover the cost for the domain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Algorithm Study (1) : Dynamic Programming</title>
      <link>https://physhik.github.io/_draft/2017-08-18-dynamicprogramming/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Aug 2017 11:25:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://physhik.github.io/_draft/2017-08-18-dynamicprogramming/</guid>
      <description>Algorithm
This is mainly a Python-implementation of the book, Cracking the coding interview, which includes examples and chosen exercises. Since I have studied algorithm of programming with Python and the Problem Solving with Algorithms and Data Structures using Python, I would review about them, too.
Actually, I started to solve the exercises of the chapter 8 (dynamic programming) because I thought I have a hole that Problem Solving with Algorithms and Data Structures using Python does not contain it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>networkx (3)</title>
      <link>https://physhik.github.io/_draft/2017-08-17-networkx_practice3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2017 21:25:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://physhik.github.io/_draft/2017-08-17-networkx_practice3/</guid>
      <description>hash hashable from glossary An object is hashable if it has a hash value which never changes during its lifetime (it needs a hash() method), and can be compared to other objects (it needs an eq() or cmp() method). Hashable objects which compare equal must have the same hash value.
Hashability makes an object usable as a dictionary key and a set member, because these data structures use the hash value internally.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>networkx (2)</title>
      <link>https://physhik.github.io/_draft/2017-08-16-networkx_practice2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2017 22:50:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://physhik.github.io/_draft/2017-08-16-networkx_practice2/</guid>
      <description>Let us start from the same graph, G of the previous posting.
import networkx as nx import matplotlib.pyplot as plt %matplotlib inline ** DiGraph
I=nx.DiGraph(G) I.nodes(data=True) [(0, {}), (1, {}), (2, {}), (3, {}), (4, {}), (5, {}), (6, {}), (7, {}), (8, {}), (9, {}), (10, {}), (11, {}), (&#39;m&#39;, {}), (&#39;p&#39;, {}), (&#39;s&#39;, {}), (&#39;a&#39;, {}), (&#39;spam&#39;, {})]  G.nodes(data=True) [(0, {}), (1, {}), (2, {}), (3, {}), (4, {}), (5, {}), (6, {}), (7, {}), (8, {}), (9, {}), (10, {}), (11, {}), (&#39;m&#39;, {}), (&#39;p&#39;, {}), (&#39;spam&#39;, {}), (&#39;s&#39;, {}), (&#39;a&#39;, {})]  G.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>networkx (1)</title>
      <link>https://physhik.github.io/_draft/2017-08-16-networkx_practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2017 16:50:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://physhik.github.io/_draft/2017-08-16-networkx_practice/</guid>
      <description>While studying deep learning, to understand graph and networks is necessary.
I try to follow the tutorial and references from the Github of networkx. The homepage of networkx is designed to have better interface, but some codes are not updated. I also added up some comments for better understanding.
import networkx as nx import matplotlib.pyplot as plt %matplotlib inline Node Initiate empty graph
G = nx.Graph() Can see the nodes as following</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>jekyll과 주어진 테마를 이용해서 만든 Github 블로그에 Disqus 추가하기</title>
      <link>https://physhik.github.io/_draft/2017-08-14-jekyll/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Aug 2017 22:50:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://physhik.github.io/_draft/2017-08-14-jekyll/</guid>
      <description>Github은 저같은 풋내기 프로그래머들에게는 환상적인 공간입니다.
이번엔 블로그를 만들어 봤는데요. 적절한 한국어로 된 설명이 드물거나 찾기 힘든 것 같아서 포스팅 해봅니다.
특히 jekyll 언어를 충분히 공부하지 않은 상태에서 특정 테마를 다운받아서 사용할 경우에 경험할 수 있는 시행착오를 범하지 않도록 하는 방향입니다.
영어로 된 게시물들은 구글링으로 쉽게 얻을 수 있습니다.
이 포스팅 또한 jekyll 홈페이지와 Sechter의 블로그의 내용의 번역이 주가 될 예정이니 더 자세한 내용을 원하시면 해당 링크로 들어가서 확인하시기 바랍니다.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://physhik.github.io/_draft/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://physhik.github.io/_draft/about/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
