<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Physics to Data Science</title>
    <link>//physhik.com/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Physics to Data Science</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2019 14:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="//physhik.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>New Blog Theme</title>
      <link>//physhik.com/2019/10/new-blog-theme/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2019 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//physhik.com/2019/10/new-blog-theme/</guid>
      <description>I decided to use my own domain instead of renting the /github.io/, and also to insert Google adsense in my blog if possible. Even if I updated my blog only 10 times since Oct, 2017, the number of visitors and their sessions were steady by Google analytics. Recently I started updating my blog again, and want to see the more industrial analytic result. At least I am sure the profit from the adsense will cover the cost for the domain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learns from Cardiologist (3)</title>
      <link>//physhik.com/2019/03/machine-learns-from-cardiologist-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2019 01:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//physhik.com/2019/03/machine-learns-from-cardiologist-3/</guid>
      <description>Open source 
The codes can be found at my Github repo. If you are familar to the models already, just see the codes. The codes are made from understanding of the research papers in Nature and the other and the open source. The host and main contributors of the linked repo are the co-authors of the original research papers. The two related research papers are easy to understand.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learns from Cardiologist (2)</title>
      <link>//physhik.com/2019/03/machine-learns-from-cardiologist-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2019 19:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//physhik.com/2019/03/machine-learns-from-cardiologist-2/</guid>
      <description>Understand literatures and the result-analysis 
Deep learning and classifications. 
The pattern recognition using deep convolutional neural network is indisputably good. It shows in various complicated image recognitions or even sound recognition. It is obvious it is going to be so good at least as the similar level of human being.

What matters is if we have enough data, and how we can preprocess the data properly for machine to learn effectively.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Macnine Learns from Cardiologist (1)</title>
      <link>//physhik.com/2019/03/macnine-learns-from-cardiologist-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2019 20:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//physhik.com/2019/03/macnine-learns-from-cardiologist-1/</guid>
      <description>Prologue 
Recenly the interest on wearing device is increasing, and the convolutional neural network (CNN) supervised learning must be one strong tool to analyse the signal of the body and predict the heart disease of our body.

When I scanned a few reseach papers, the 1 dimensional signal and the regular pattern of the heart beat reminds me of musical signals I researched in that it requires a signal process and neural network, and it has much potential to bring healthier life to humar races1, so I want to present the introductory post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Youtube Data API on GCP</title>
      <link>//physhik.com/2019/02/youtube-data-api-on-gcp/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2019 02:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//physhik.com/2019/02/youtube-data-api-on-gcp/</guid>
      <description>To architect low cost and well-performing server, many companies use cloud service such as Amazon AWS, Google clound platform (GCP). I have used AWS EC2 with GPU and S3 storage for my deep learning research at Soundcorset.

AWS and GCP opened many cloud platform services, and to build the data pipeline and to manage the data effectively, need to learn the command line tool and API. In this post, I will discuss the Google Youtube data API because recently I studied.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clean Coding and Short Run Time</title>
      <link>//physhik.com/2019/02/clean-coding-and-short-run-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2019 16:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//physhik.com/2019/02/clean-coding-and-short-run-time/</guid>
      <description>Today I want to discuss purely about coding itself. I wish this post is helpful for someone want to transit his career from a pure researcher to a programmer. I have been a researcher rather than a programmer. I would just want to execute something to see the result I wanted to see. If the run time is too long or my computer has no enough memory to run the code, it was a sign of new purchase to me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Revisited Variational Inference</title>
      <link>//physhik.com/2018/02/revisited-variational-inference/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2018 23:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//physhik.com/2018/02/revisited-variational-inference/</guid>
      <description>A few days ago, I was asked what the variational method is, and I found my previous post, Variational Method for Optimization, barely explain some basic of variational method. Thus, I would do it in this post.

Data concerned in machine learning are ruled by physics of informations. It sounds quite abstract, so I will present an example of dynamic mechanics. Let us consider a ball thrown with velocity v=($v_x$, $v_y$) at x = (x, y), and under the vertical gravity with constant g.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rough Review of WaveGAN</title>
      <link>//physhik.com/2018/02/rough-review-of-wavegan/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2018 23:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//physhik.com/2018/02/rough-review-of-wavegan/</guid>
      <description>Around a week ago, on ArXiv, an interesting research paper appeared, which is about the music style transfer using GAN, which is also my main topic for recent few months. Around a week ago, on arXiv, an interesting research paper appeared, which can be applied to the music style transfer using GAN, which is also my main topic for recent few months. There are already many researches on the style transfer of the images, and one of my main projects now is making the style transfer in music.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to GAN </title>
      <link>//physhik.com/2017/12/introduction-to-gan/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Dec 2017 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//physhik.com/2017/12/introduction-to-gan/</guid>
      <description>I want to introduce some GAN model I have studied after I started working for the digital signal process. I will skip technical detail of the introduction. My goal is to provide a minimal background information.

Revolution in deep learning 
As we have seen at the post of VAE, generative model can be useful in machine learning. Not only one can classify the data but also can generate new data we do not have.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Test Progressive Growing of GAN from the Github Source</title>
      <link>//physhik.com/2017/12/how-to-test-progressive-growing-of-gan-from-the-github-source/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Dec 2017 23:50:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//physhik.com/2017/12/how-to-test-progressive-growing-of-gan-from-the-github-source/</guid>
      <description>NVIDIA research team published a paper, Progressive Growing of GANs for Improved Quality, Stability, and Variation, and the source code on Github a month ago.

I went through some trials and errors to run the codes properly, so I want to make it easier to you. Why I think this post will be helpful is the Github page is not supporting to post issues to ask and answer for inquiries.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning to Learn by Gradient Descent by Gradient Descent</title>
      <link>//physhik.com/2017/09/learning-to-learn-by-gradient-descent-by-gradient-descent/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Sep 2017 23:50:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//physhik.com/2017/09/learning-to-learn-by-gradient-descent-by-gradient-descent/</guid>
      <description>I had a trip to Quebec city for 4 days. Behind the lingering from the travel, I prepared for the meetup this week. I could not join it because of birthday dinner with my girlfriend. However, I studied the original paper seriously, and the topic involves some interesting ideas, so I want to introduce about it.

Long short term memory (LSTM) 
To understand the paper, precedently, need to understand LSTM.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Variational Autoencoder</title>
      <link>//physhik.com/2017/09/variational-autoencoder/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2017 23:50:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//physhik.com/2017/09/variational-autoencoder/</guid>
      <description>Mark who I met in machine learning study meetup had recommended me to study a research paper about discrete variational autoencoder. I have read today. As so does variational inference, it includes many mathematical equations, but what the author wants to tell was very straightforward. Two previous posts, Variational Method, Independent Component Analysis, are relevant to the following discussion.

Autoencoder 
To understand the paper, above all, we need to know what the autoencoder is and what variational autoencoder is.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neural Network (5) : Very Simple Boltzmann Machine</title>
      <link>//physhik.com/2017/09/neural-network-5-very-simple-boltzmann-machine/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Sep 2017 23:50:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//physhik.com/2017/09/neural-network-5-very-simple-boltzmann-machine/</guid>
      <description>Stochastic Hopfield net 
Boltzmann machine is nothing but stochastic Hopfield net1. If you did not yet read the post of the Hopfield net in the blog, just go read it. I assume the readers are familiar to it, and directly use many results we had in the post. The magic of deep learning which we have discussed a couple of times works here, too. Such as $\epsilon$-greedy off-policy algorithm2, the stochastic character of the binary units allows the machine occasionally increase its energy to escape from poor local minima.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Graphviz</title>
      <link>//physhik.com/2017/09/graphviz/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2017 16:20:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//physhik.com/2017/09/graphviz/</guid>
      <description>Bike algorithm 
I like riding a bike. Because my knee are not healthy now, I cannot ride a bike much. However, even little riding makes me feel good. Today it occurs to me if I am addicted at riding a bike. During riding a bike, I was thinking about the algorithm commands me. Silly me thought it is funny.

Thus, I tried to make a flowchart of the algorithm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neural Network (4) : Deep Reinforcement Learning, Q-learning</title>
      <link>//physhik.com/2017/09/neural-network-4-deep-reinforcement-learning-q-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2017 23:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//physhik.com/2017/09/neural-network-4-deep-reinforcement-learning-q-learning/</guid>
      <description>Judgement Day 
It is the first time I did not post for 4 days. I was too busy to prepare for the meetup this week. The day before yesterday meetup topic was the reinforcement learning as I mentioned at previous post. It is not a long research paper, but includes 143 references. Ah, not my favorite. This A Brief Survey of Deep Reinforcement Learning did not explain the detail of what I am interested in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neural Network (3) : Hopfield Net</title>
      <link>//physhik.com/2017/09/neural-network-3-hopfield-net/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2017 13:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//physhik.com/2017/09/neural-network-3-hopfield-net/</guid>
      <description>Binary Hopfield net using Hebbian learning 
We want to study Hopfield net from the simple case. Hopfield net is a fully connected feedback network. A feedback network is a network that is not a feedforward network, and in a feedforward network, all the connections are directed. All the connections in our example will be bi-directed. This symmetric property of the weight is important property of the Hopfield net.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ising Model</title>
      <link>//physhik.com/2017/09/ising-model/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Sep 2017 23:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//physhik.com/2017/09/ising-model/</guid>
      <description>Why Ising model : 3 reasons for relevance 
 Studying Ising model can be useful to understand phase transition of various systems.  
 Hopfield network or Boltzmann machine to the neural network is just a generalized form of Ising model.  
 Ising model is also useful as a statistical model in its own right.  
Ising model $\boldsymbol{x}$ is the state of an Ising model with $N$ spins be a vector in which each component $\boldsymbol x_n$ takes values $-1$ or $+1$.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neural Network (2) : Inference Using Perceptron and MCMC</title>
      <link>//physhik.com/2017/09/neural-network-2-inference-using-perceptron-and-mcmc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2017 16:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//physhik.com/2017/09/neural-network-2-inference-using-perceptron-and-mcmc/</guid>
      <description>Single neuron still has a lot to say 
In the post of the first neural network tutorial, we studied a perceptron as a simple supervised learning machine. The perceptron is an amazing structure to understanding inference.

In the post of the first neural network tutorial, I said I would leave you to find the objective function and and draw the plot of it. I just introduce here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MCMC (7) : Slice Sampling</title>
      <link>//physhik.com/2017/09/mcmc-7-slice-sampling/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2017 17:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//physhik.com/2017/09/mcmc-7-slice-sampling/</guid>
      <description>Slice sampling algorithm 
A single transition $(x,u) \rightarrow (x&amp;rsquo;,u&amp;rsquo;)$ of a one-dimensional slice sampling algorithm has the following steps.

(1). evaluate $P^* (x)$
(2). draw a vertical coordinate $u&amp;rsquo; \sim$ Uniform$(0,P^* (x))$
(3). create a horizontal interval $(x_l, x_r)$ enclosing $x$
&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; 3a. draw $r \sim$ Uniform$(0,1)$
&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; 3b. $x_l := x-rw$
&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; 3c. $x_r := x+(1-r)w$
&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; 3d. while $(P^* (x_l) &amp;gt; u&amp;rsquo;)$ ${x_l := x-rw}$</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bayesian Inference Examples</title>
      <link>//physhik.com/2017/09/bayesian-inference-examples/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Sep 2017 12:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//physhik.com/2017/09/bayesian-inference-examples/</guid>
      <description>I assume that the readers know the Bayes&amp;rsquo; rule already. If you are not familiar to it, read any kind of textbook about probability, data science, and machine learning. I recommend the book, which I learned Bayes&amp;rsquo; rule. Bayesians say that you cannot do inference without making assumptions. Thus, Bayesians also use probabilities to describe inferences. The author in the chapter 2 introduces some rules of probability theory and introduces more about assumptions in inference in the chapter 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MCMC (6): Gibbs Sampling and Overrelaxation</title>
      <link>//physhik.com/2017/09/mcmc-6-gibbs-sampling-and-overrelaxation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 22:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//physhik.com/2017/09/mcmc-6-gibbs-sampling-and-overrelaxation/</guid>
      <description>Efficient Monte Carlo sampling 
This post is on the extension of the post about Hamiltonian Monte Carlo method. Therefore, I assume the readers already read the post. Overrelaxation also reduces the random property of the Monte Carlo sampling, and speeds up the convergence of the Markov chain.

Gibbs sampling 
In advance of studying over relaxation, we study Gibbs sampling. In the general case of a system with K variables, a single iteration involves sampling one parameter at a time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clustering (2) : Soft K-mean</title>
      <link>//physhik.com/2017/08/clustering-2-soft-k-mean/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2017 13:40:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//physhik.com/2017/08/clustering-2-soft-k-mean/</guid>
      <description>Hard K-means and responsibilities 
If you did not read the first part of the clustering series. Please go check it out. I use the same data points and this post starts from troubleshooting the hard K-means algorithm in the previous post.

In the previous post, we defined assignment. The equivalent representation of this assignment of points to clusters is given by responsibilities, $r^{(n)}_k$. In the assignment step, we set $r^{(n)}_k$ to one if mean k is the closest mean to datapoint $ {\textbf x}^{(n)}$; otherwise, $r^{(n)}_k$ is zero.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neural Network (1): Perceptron and Stochastic Gradient Descent</title>
      <link>//physhik.com/2017/08/neural-network-1-perceptron-and-stochastic-gradient-descent/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2017 19:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//physhik.com/2017/08/neural-network-1-perceptron-and-stochastic-gradient-descent/</guid>
      <description>Single neuron is amazing 
One of the lessons I had during physics program is that we should start to understand small thing deeply however complicated the system which you want to know is. Not just it is easier but also it helps a lot to understand the more complex ones.

Neural network is often compared to black magic. We do not understand why and how exactly so effective it is, but it makes great estimations in some specific matters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Independent Component Analysis and Covariant Learning</title>
      <link>//physhik.com/2017/08/independent-component-analysis-and-covariant-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2017 10:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//physhik.com/2017/08/independent-component-analysis-and-covariant-learning/</guid>
      <description>Generative model 
Generative model is a model for generating all variables including outputs. I will give a very simple example with strong assumptions.

Data $\boldsymbol{x^{(n)} } $ are generated by an unknown matrix, $\boldsymbol{G}$.
$$ \boldsymbol{x} = \boldsymbol{G}~\boldsymbol{s} $$
The goal is to find the source variable $\boldsymbol{s}$.
 we assume that the number of sources is equal to the number of observations We assume that the latent variables are independently distributed, with marginal distributions We assume that the vector $\boldsymbol{x}$ is generated without noise for simplicity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Variational Method for Optimization</title>
      <link>//physhik.com/2017/08/variational-method-for-optimization/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Aug 2017 01:10:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//physhik.com/2017/08/variational-method-for-optimization/</guid>
      <description>I announce over and over that the chronicle ordering of the post are irrelevant for beginners&amp;rsquo; favor. There are many blanks I skipped. I would fill the holes later.

Variational method 
During my physics coursework and researches, I used this method countlessly. I even had a book of the name. It is quite simple, but also as big topic as being a book. Simply put, it is a technique to find equations and solutions (sometimes approximate solutions) by extremizing functionals which is mainly just integrals of fields, and treat the functions in the integral, as parameters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MCMC (5) : Hamiltonian Monte Carlo Method</title>
      <link>//physhik.com/2017/08/mcmc-5-hamiltonian-monte-carlo-method/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Aug 2017 19:10:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//physhik.com/2017/08/mcmc-5-hamiltonian-monte-carlo-method/</guid>
      <description>Yay! Finally something more directly from physics to data science. We will also have a chance to see how Metropolis-Hastings algorithm works!

The Hamiltonian Monte Carlo method is a kind of Metropolis-Hastings method. One of the weak points of Monte Carlo sampling comes up with random walks. Hamiltonian Monte Carlo method (HMC) is an approach to reducing the randomizing in algorithm of the sampling.

The original name was hybrid Monte Carlo method.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MCMC (4) : Rejection Sampling</title>
      <link>//physhik.com/2017/08/mcmc-4-rejection-sampling/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2017 02:10:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//physhik.com/2017/08/mcmc-4-rejection-sampling/</guid>
      <description>In advance, I will proceed in the extension of the previous post. I will use the same target distribution function and the similar Gaussian disposal distribution. Even Python script will be better understood if you&amp;rsquo;ve already read the previous post about importance sampling.

The rejection sampling could be the most familiar Monte Carlo sampling. When need to introduce Monte Carlo method to somebody, it is very intuitive and effective to give an example of computing the area of the circle (or anything) by using random samples.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MCMC (3) : Importance Sampling</title>
      <link>//physhik.com/2017/08/mcmc-3-importance-sampling/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Aug 2017 02:10:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//physhik.com/2017/08/mcmc-3-importance-sampling/</guid>
      <description>Importance sampling is the first sampling method I faced when I studied Monte Carlo method. Nevertheless, I haven&amp;rsquo;t seen many examples for the importance sampling. Maybe it is because the importance sampling is not effective for high dimensional systems. The weak point of the importance sampling is that the performance of it is determined by how well we choose the disposal distribution close to the target distribution.

Here, I will present a simple example of the importance sampling.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MCMC (2) : Exact Monte Carlo Method</title>
      <link>//physhik.com/2017/08/mcmc-2-exact-monte-carlo-method/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2017 02:10:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//physhik.com/2017/08/mcmc-2-exact-monte-carlo-method/</guid>
      <description>Exact Markov chain Monte Carlo sampling 
I don&amp;rsquo;t like the naming. The word exact could mislead us to understand the concept. Anyway I used the word in the title because it was the title of the chapter of the book &amp;ldquo;Information Theory, Inference, and Learning Algorithms&amp;rdquo; by David Mackay, which I studied to learn the theory.
The different names of it are perfect simulation and coupling from the past.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MCMC (1) : Monte Carlo Method and Metropolis-Hastings Sampling</title>
      <link>//physhik.com/2017/08/mcmc-1-monte-carlo-method-and-metropolis-hastings-sampling/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2017 14:10:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//physhik.com/2017/08/mcmc-1-monte-carlo-method-and-metropolis-hastings-sampling/</guid>
      <description>Monte Carlo method 
Monte Carlo method is useful in Bayesian data modeling because maximizing posterior probability is often very difficult and fitting a Gaussian becomes hard.

Monte Carlo method becomes valuable in that we want to generate samples in some situation, and also want to estimate some expectation values of various functions.

What we deal with in this post is only small part of Monte Carlo method.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Add Mathjax to Jekyll blog</title>
      <link>//physhik.com/2017/08/add-mathjax-to-jekyll-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Aug 2017 12:10:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//physhik.com/2017/08/add-mathjax-to-jekyll-blog/</guid>
      <description>Add mathjax 
The another good thing of Jekyll blog1 is that we can finally use math formula in it.
$$ \nabla \times \vec{B} = 0 $$
There was troubles when I tried to include some formula in Github README.md file.

Haixing Hu&amp;rsquo;s blog was helpful to do it.

Need to fix 3 kinds of files in total.

1. make a new mathjax_support.html file in _include folder</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clustering (1), Hard K-means and its Failure</title>
      <link>//physhik.com/2017/08/clustering-1-hard-k-means-and-its-failure/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2017 03:40:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//physhik.com/2017/08/clustering-1-hard-k-means-and-its-failure/</guid>
      <description>As I mentioned at the previous posting, one of the purposes of this blog is to supplement the Github of my data science study. I will gradually post and present all the iPython notebooks or Mathematica notebooks.

I felt there&amp;rsquo;s no good Python tutorial for spectral clustering (at least from my search). Who can&amp;rsquo;t use scikit-learn among who is serious about machine learning. It was not difficult to find the theory of spectral clustering as well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adding Disqus to a Jekyll Blog</title>
      <link>//physhik.com/2017/08/adding-disqus-to-a-jekyll-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Aug 2017 23:50:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//physhik.com/2017/08/adding-disqus-to-a-jekyll-blog/</guid>
      <description>Github is a fantastic space for someone like me to try to learn something new.

This time I have built a blog powered by jekyll and Github. This posting is targetting a novice who especially used a theme, and who is trying to add a disqus in the blog. Hope it helps them not to experience the trials and errors I had.

I found jekyll homepage and Sechter&amp;rsquo;s blog good.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to Jekyll!</title>
      <link>//physhik.com/2017/08/welcome-to-jekyll/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2017 18:40:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//physhik.com/2017/08/welcome-to-jekyll/</guid>
      <description>You’ll find this post in your _posts directory. Go ahead and edit it and re-build the site to see your changes. You can rebuild the site in many different ways, but the most common way is to run jekyll serve, which launches a web server and auto-regenerates your site when a file is updated.
To add new posts, simply add a file in the _posts directory that follows the convention YYYY-MM-DD-name-of-post.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>