<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mathematica on Physics to Data Science</title>
    <link>https://physhik.github.io/tags/mathematica/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Mathematica on Physics to Data Science</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Sep 2017 12:30:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://physhik.github.io/tags/mathematica/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Bayesian Inference Examples</title>
      <link>https://physhik.github.io/2017/09/bayesian-inference-examples/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Sep 2017 12:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://physhik.github.io/2017/09/bayesian-inference-examples/</guid>
      <description>I assume that the readers know the Bayes&amp;rsquo; rule already. If you are not familiar to it, read any kind of textbook about probability, data science, and machine learning. I recommend the book, which I learned Bayes&amp;rsquo; rule. Bayesians say that you cannot do inference without making assumptions. Thus, Bayesians also use probabilities to describe inferences. The author in the chapter 2 introduces some rules of probability theory and introduces more about assumptions in inference in the chapter 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Variational Method for Optimization</title>
      <link>https://physhik.github.io/2017/08/variational-method-for-optimization/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Aug 2017 01:10:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://physhik.github.io/2017/08/variational-method-for-optimization/</guid>
      <description>I announce over and over that the chronicle ordering of the post are irrelevant for beginners&amp;rsquo; favor. There are many blanks I skipped. I would fill the holes later.

Variational method 
During my physics coursework and researches, I used this method countlessly. I even had a book of the name. It is quite simple, but also as big topic as being a book. Simply put, it is a technique to find equations and solutions (sometimes approximate solutions) by extremizing functionals which is mainly just integrals of fields, and treat the functions in the integral, as parameters.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>